TSION ZELEKE

My Contact

+251-913-379232

Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

https://github.com/TsionZerihun/

www.linkedin.com/in/tsion-zeleke/

Soft Skill

- python(Django, Flask)
- Javascript(JQuery, React, Node.js, Angualr, Express)
- SQL(MySQL,NoSQL,MongoDB)
- HTML,CSS
- C#(.NET)
- JAVA
- Docker
- Agile/Scrum/waterfall
- Visual studio code
- Anaconda
- wordpress

Education Background

ALX Holberton Software Engineering Programme

ALX Software Engineering Programme with a specialization in Back End Development Completed in 2023

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science computer science degree Completed in july, 2017

Achievements

- · Arba Minch Institute of Technology and CSIT department for participating in CSIT club competition and exhibition with an Android application entitled "Android Based Campus guide
- "UNDP involve me" program for participation in a 1-minute filmmaking competition. •

About Me

I would like to introduce myself as a highly organized individual who has a passion for solving problems and coming up with new ideas. I have experience with a wide range of software and Hardware applications through academic projects during my first degree of study as well as the ALX SE program. Working on a project that changes people's lives is the long-term goal I have. I have the vision to enhance my country (Ethiopia) as well as Africa through automation and bringing new solutions and innovations.

Professional Experience

FREELANCER I 2022 - Present

· Developed custom software solutions for clients using Djangobackend and react-frontend

- Build APIs with Node.js and Express.
- Currently working on a user dashboard software that uses .NET Core 7.0 for backend development
- Built Ecom website using MERN stack
- Worked on a project on developing REST API for the Y-Maze test (Y-Maze test is a behavioral test for measuring the willingness of rodents to explore (new) environments
- · Worked on simple Python projects
 - Extract images from Word document template and place them in folders with Python
 - Scrape data from the webpage and paste it into Excel
 - Building indexing and retrieval using preprocessed datasets

Agriculture Transformation Agency | ATA Data Analyst Apr, 2019 - Sep 2020

Key responsibilities:

- Coding and running Automated Test Scripts for large data sets using VBScript in Excel
- · Identify and acquire relevant quantitative and qualitative data using a range of applied and pragmatic techniques, and control data to ensure validity and accuracy.
- · Plan, prioritize and manage workstreams from start to finish, including data collection, analysis and content development,
- stakeholder input and validation, and ensure required timelines and quality standards.

TAL Apparel | IT System Support Executive Oct, 2017 - Mar 2019

- Design and Implement the organization's Networks
- Network Database and Administrating, troubleshooting and configuration
- Maintaining records of software licenses
- Support and train the staff on how to utilize the company's software.